<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A Witchy Blog 🧙‍♀</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/</link><description>Recent content on A Witchy Blog 🧙‍♀</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://computerwitch.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating through Grief</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/jun-S3WKb9TmRxo-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Navigating through Grief" />&lt;p>My father passed away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And grief became a fever dream where I got to relive all my lost innocence. From shutting the door of the fridge to the smallest possible crease to see when the light would turn off. To the childish game of only stepping in the lithe figure of his shadow… To hearing the clinks of his keys before the door would even open.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a tower, a solid structure, built on the crumbling ground. I am no longer myself. I rarely ever say what I really think I just choose the most fun interactions. I say things I don’t mean, and I always chase distractions. Inconsequently, going from one long string of bad decisions to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe dad would’ve said that when it rains, you set up your barrels and when it winds, you start your turbines. My dad would’ve said to be my own boss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But his death was just insurmountable. I suffered through it. From the moment he fell into a coma, to the last time I hugged him, a corpse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief is seeing a recipe for mashed potatoes and bawling my eyes because the last time that I made them for him, they weren’t just like he liked them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief is guilt and loss and pain and missing him like a little kid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief feels like being a little girl again and anxiously waiting for him to come back from work so that he could pick me up in his arms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief is all the times he was proud of me and disappointed by me balled up into one unbearable feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief is me being irrational, delusional, and heartbroken more than I ever was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And grief is desolation because there is no way of seeing you or talking to you and it feels like you only exist behind me and I’m only getting further ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Grief is not knowing if I miss you more than I love you or if I love you more than I miss you.
&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 99;
flex-basis: 237px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/missyoudad.jpeg" data-size="1057x1067">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/missyoudad.jpeg"
width="1057"
height="1067"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/missyoudad_hu841f7167e75ca34e5f5468762d4375fa_84506_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/missyoudad_hu841f7167e75ca34e5f5468762d4375fa_84506_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ad Memoriam">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Ad Memoriam&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I was a Financial Criminal on Habbo as a Child</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/childhood-memoir/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/childhood-memoir/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/childhood-memoir/EPF2005.png" alt="Featured image of post I was a Financial Criminal on Habbo as a Child" />&lt;p>“Think… Think of something that is important to you…” The bird chirped on the sill of the window. “Of how the colors blend, of the smell of packed mortadella sandwich lunches, yoghurt and gouache. Of kindergarten and sunny days. Of how happy and full your heart was. Of…” And then it flew away, mid-sentence, not letting my imagination catch up to what the chirps and birdsongs could’ve meant.
I can’t really think of anything significant. Except that the early days of my childhood were golden, pure and untainted… Simple and fun days. Perhaps, it is only my perception that makes it so, and lifts off my chest the burden of reminiscence. Maybe, my mood is good today and I am unbothered to think of the discomfort and negativity of the past. I do know my mood congruency and psychology theories well after all. Dare I say that I might have been happy? I’m glad I damaged my brain enough in the last few years to erase a good portion of the negativity and discomfort of my past. I must have killed a fair share of my neurons too… In a way I am dumber, but I’d also like to believe that I’m way happier.
Now to be honest, I’m uncomfortable in this endeavor. I’m not at ease with having to talk to myself, in forcing myself to pry away to find something significant to say; something that “a lesson can be learned from”&amp;hellip; Life is chaos. There is no lesson to be learned from misery, or of all the terrible, horrible, inexplicable, and frankly unnecessary events of life. Everything has been desecrated and commercialized, because people, like vultures find a delectable pleasure in the pain of others. I’m amazed at the insanity of packaging suffering into something ‘inspirational’ and ‘thoughtful’. I&amp;rsquo;d rather speak of what speaks to me: a good memory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sixteen years ago, there was a small infinity in a sepia two-bedroom apartment. The living room was the soul of our home, and where we’d essentially come together as a family. The floors were lava to be crossed from the couch sentinels, and under the dining table: luxurious forts would be built with soft blanket floors and cushiony walls. MBC channel and Cartoon Networks blazed our imaginations even further. We made up stories, believed them even… Ghosts breathed in on our necks while we were sleeping in our beds, dolls were secretly planning to murder us like Chucky, and maybe Pennywise was living in the sink&amp;rsquo;s drain. The living room also had one the most central things to my childhood, and possibly the push behind my current major in college: the stationary computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a child of a strict middle class family, I wasn’t spoiled or allowed much extravagance. My needs were generously met, and I was content, but of course the heart always yearns for more than it needs. I had taken to playing an online game: ‘Habbo’, and my parents would not, absolutely not, buy me the virtual coins that I was so desperate for. Habbo was a game in which players could make avatars, visit and decorate rooms, trade all at the cost of Habbo credits: the ultra-consumerist utopia. Thus, began the saga of virtual financial crime. It was common to conduct mini-scams, and I masterminded my way into one of the greatest heist I’ve ever conducted to this day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a warm summer night; song of cicadas, mosquito buzz, sweat and thin tile pattern blankets. One of the many summer nights where my sister and I couldn’t sleep, but that we still had to. We were afraid of dad finding us using the computer in the middle of the night. Hastily pulling out the plug would not work, as he’d pat the central unit to check if it was warm and then instantly see through our bluff. It was a game of cat and mouse. Of course, rules are meant to be broken! Especially, when you are a kid and you had your virtual empire of financial crime to run. The day of our greatest heist, we had learned about a glitch that made a very cheap item: a pixelated dog ball, look like a black hole. No one had ever heard of a ‘black hole’ item, so it was a perfect opportunity to deceive and bluff other gullible kids on the server about it: “The limited edition super rare black hole in the wall”. Thus, trading it for an actual rare item or selling it for an expensive item. My sister spent the majority of the day trading or seeing how to buy as much as possible of the dog balls to trick some poor souls into buying them, and before we could sell them the clock was already dangerously ticking near our bedtime.
Evidently, one of our fears was that the admins of Habbo would catch on to the glitch and would patch it overnight. We felt the pressing urgency to sell all of the glitch dog balls we’ve accumulated, or half of our capital would’ve vanished for nothing. Mom served us dinner, and I asked if we could sleep in the living room as our shared bedroom was too hot. It took some convincing to not raise any suspicions. And so very few hours later, after pretending to be asleep and passing dad checking on us, we awoke to conduct our evil master plan. Per precaution, I snuck into the kitchen to get freezer packs to cool the central unit with. I wasn’t fazed by the pins and needles the cold packs sunk into my hands: my heart was pumping out of my chest from the thrill of this forbidden adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back into the living room, my sister nodded at me as she turned the computer on. No talking, no fast typing either, only scheming silence. I angled the cold packs on the sides of the central unit, and stood next to my sister seated in the swivel chair: like Dr. Evil’s mini-me. She swung the mouse to open the browser, then typed the domain and logged into our joint Habbo account. The strategy was simple and straightforward: befriend and betray. We would find a trading room, chat with users and entire them about our sham rare item, and then get them to buy for as high as possible. As an old Moroccan adage says: “the greedy is vanquished by the liar”. It was battle with time, a parkour in its own rank: many buyers were interested, and we were busy fooling them. My sister would take care of most of the typing, while I controlled the mouse: starting trades, and blocking users before they realize that the ‘Black hole’ was in fact a dog ball in their inventory. Sale after sale, we had dollar signs in our eyes, and we were slowly losing our initial focused and alert composure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dad peaked his head through the door, and immediately spotted us: contrasted by the light of the monitor in the darkness of the living room. He immediately started screaming and giving us an earful. We both were terrified, and retreated to the furthest corner. Dad didn’t even bother properly unplugging the computer, he just grabbed the central unit: along to squirm at the cold packs, and for him to be even angrier. My sister looked at me, paler than a ghost, her eyes were wide open and grabbed my hand to run. But where to? There was no escape. I felt blind terror as we both fled as fast as we could to lock ourselves in the bathroom. Hyperventilating, scared… I locked eyes with my sister, and soon, we burst out laughing as hard as we could. By that point, we had woken up everyone. Mom knocked at the bathroom door and urged us to come out. We eventually did, and yes, we were grounded the worst grounding of our lives. But I remember sleeping giddy and happy for some reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this day, I still nostalgically log into my Habbo account… Well not as much as I used to but at least once every year to remember the good old days. I wonder if my childhood as a scammer, and my passion for computers had a role to play in me choosing computer science as my major and future career. It’s obvious that scamming is not a good thing to do, but that was and is still the reality of many children who couldn’t buy coins in virtual games but still wanted the good things in life. I have no regrets. It was fun while it lasted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moral Development in Adolescents</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/moral-development-adolescents/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/moral-development-adolescents/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/moral-development-adolescents/patrick-buck-iPpy3Mupk8k-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Moral Development in Adolescents" />&lt;p>Moral development in adolescence is a recent area of interest in psychological research that achieved maturity. An indicator of that is the numerous published literatures itemizing moral development in adolescence. The interest may push us to want to investigate the reason for which moral development has become a popular topic of interest amongst researchers. The reasons for the attention paid may lie in political and theoretical aims (Hart &amp;amp; Carlo, 2005). Political research is motivated by public belief and funded mostly by federal funding of research, while theory research is offered by genuine theoretical opportunities in the study of adolescents’ moral capacities. The general attitudes towards adolescents have been negative: only 15% of American adults in a national poll to describe adolescent have characterized teenagers positively, and the majority have suggested moral shortcomings such “impolite” and “irresponsible” (Duffett et al., 1999). In the same survey, when asked to classify the most crucial problem facing adolescents and young adults, American adults responded that it was the deficiency of moral values. Given the overrall perception of adolescents as morally deficient, it is self-evident that policy makers, and researchers alike, would be politically motivated to fund research on the topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-foundations-of-morality-in-adolescence">The Foundations of Morality in Adolescence&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While for a big part literature has been misled by the misconception that most adolescents are immoral, it has, however, capitalized on the theme that adolescence is the bridging foundation of moral capacities in adulthood. Researchers suggested that moral models, such as Gandhi, can be comprehended through the study of the development of moral devoirs of adolescents and young adults. The supposition that adult moral character is shaped during adolescence is implicit. By the motive of understanding and ultimately mastering the influences that act on the adolescent, the moral development of adults are apt to be guided to become better persons. In their article, Lawford et al. (2009) put forward the same idea by suggesting that the generativity, the motivation to be concerned about the future and to contribute to the future generations, takes root during adolescence. The result of their research indicates that there is a correlation between present young adults with a caring personality towards others and their positive relationships with parents and peer during adolescence. Likewise, Smetana and Killen (2015) have suggested that community involvement, reflecting the obligation of adult’s morals, is essentially intertwined with peers, family and church or religious community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A secondary important theme across the research on moral developments in adolescent has been that adolescence is distinguished by unique qualities that render it developmentally and distinctively different from childhood such as sexual maturation, increased decision-making, heightened pressures from peers and family, and the search for self-identity. As a result, moral character can go through an important transformation between the stages of childhood and adulthood. Surely, in Western societies, a distinguishing quality of adolescents in comparison to children is that they devote more time with their peers, while spending less time with their parents. Consequently, adolescents are likelier to be influenced by the influences of peers than children are. Children are also more dependent on their parents than adolescents are. Inferring those variables, Coie and colleagues (1998) centralized on the influence of adolescents’ peers on the inclining and maintaining of delinquent behavior. Adolescence is characterized by distinctive contexts such as transition into schools, work, romantic interests, burgeoning of sexuality, and the prominence of peers, along with all the relationships and challenges that comes with those transitions. The findings of the research painted a complex image of delinquent behavior being influenced by peers, but also influences in the realm of family and schools. Adolescents are likelier to engage in delinquent behavior if they form friendships with delinquent peers or spend a lot of time in unstructured socializing with their friends (Haynie &amp;amp; Osgood, 2005). Therefore, we can reasonably assume that shaping of moral character during adolescence is more influenced by peers than parents as well as the parenting style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important aspect of moral development during adolescence was purposed by the article of Eisenberg and al. (1998) pointing out the substantial research showing varieties of skills and expertise relating to moral development and character developed during adolescence more-so than in childhood. For instance, in adolescence, the abilities of adopt the view of others, understanding one’s self and solving interpersonal problems are majorly developed than they are in childhood. However, the advancement of those abilities is founded upon the achievements and disappointments of childhood, thereupon, adolescence is not a unique set apart psychological stage. Instead, it is a stage of deterministic refinements of the tools that make a person able to commit to their moral lives more effectively than it is normally realizable for a child.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="socialization-and-morality-in-adolescents">Socialization and Morality in Adolescents&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Altogether, special distinguishing situations, relationships, pressures, expectations, and search for self, make adolescence a special period of interest to observe moral development. Adolescence is also the leading stage into adulthood, and just as childhood constitutes a foundational base for the skills of moral character to be refined and developed; adolescence is the base of morals in young adulthood. Thus, to be concise, the psychological processes of moral development during adolescence can be quantified through the lens of peers, parents, practices within the culture, and social institutions. In childhood, most of the contacts with the outside world are mediated and structured by the parents and adults. Parents organize playdates, most times watch the children or babysit them, keep track of their contacts with social institutions, and guide their involvement in religious and practices within the culture, hence the influent power of parents on moral socialization in childhood. However, for adolescents, there tends eto less control and regulation as they are expected to become more responsible by adjusting to newer obligations. Adolescents and adults alike are in an affluent milieu of peers, family, establishments, and cultural as well as religious practices. Although, adolescents change way faster than adults do as by the age of thirty personality as well as moral character tends to plateau (James, 1890).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore, due to the importance of peers and family, the bulk of research on moral development and socialization has focused on the influence of socialization agents, however, although the focus on social factors, the study of moral development of adolescence reminds us of other important factors, often neglected, such as the role of genes and epigenetics. Scholars have noted evidence on the genetic basis for moral tendencies like aggression, altruism, as well as temperament (Eisenberg &amp;amp; Fabes, 1998). Puberty marks the start of adolescence and is significant to the re-emergence of the processes with a biological basis that could potentially influence moral development in adolescence. The maturations of puberty, which are biologically based, enhance and influence emotions, social behaviors, and emotional receptivity. Additionally, hormonal changes in puberty have been linked to aggressivity and irritability, adolescent crisis, which are believed to mollify altruistic and aggressive behavior (Fabes, Carlo, Kupanoff, &amp;amp; Laible, 1998). It is suggested that certain hormones and neurotransmitters are responsible, in part, for aggressiveness and pro-social behavior (Carlo &amp;amp; Bevins, 2002). Other studies have focused on brain activation while taking moral decisions (De Quervain, Fischbacher, Treyer, Schellhammer, Schnyder, Buck, &amp;amp; Fehr, 2004).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Peers are important because they give the chance of “role-taking opportunities” and reveal novel moral behaviors to adolescents (Hart, Atkins, Markey, &amp;amp; Youniss, 2004). During adolescence, moral dilemmas become fully fledged in their moral consequences to the self and to others. For instance, adolescents often develop romantic interests and through that experience: they must act as moral agent and make personally significant decision with extensive implications. Adolescence offers the contingency of becoming agentic in various responsibilities, duties, and social roles. For instance, adolescents have access to work (part-time job), community service, extracurriculars, and the increase of participation in socially regulated behaviors like driving etc. which places them in situations of moral decision-making. Additionally, adolescents have access to different media and social networks, which provide them with unique socializing experiences. Movies, novels, and series directed at a teen and adult audience provide novel moral information and situation where adolescents are able to reflect on their own moral beliefs and the impact of their actions on their surroundings and other. Without doubt, socializing experiences have an important impact, as they are intertwined with the influence of authority figures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, it is important to note the influence of culture. Cultural expectations and traditions are important in defining the moral systems of children (Whiting &amp;amp; Edwards, 1988). Morality is embedded in culture, as it the dynamic play of norms, perceptions, and understanding. Although, there are multiple levels of morality at multiple levels of the individual and contexts, such as familial, academic, or professional. Adolescents navigate through those levels and contexts, and the influence either genetic, social, or psychological brings us closer to understand the complexity of moral development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="bibliography">&lt;strong>Bibliography&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Carlo, G., &amp;amp; Bevins, R. A. (2002). The need for proximal mechanisms to understand individual differences in altruism. Behavioral and Brain Sciences (Commentary), 25, 255–256.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coie, J. D., &amp;amp; Dodge, K. A. (1998). Aggression and antisocial behavior. In W. Damon (Series Ed.) &amp;amp; N. Eisenberg (Volume Ed.), Handbook of child psychology, Vol. 3: Social, emotional, and personality development (5th ed., pp. 779–862). New York: John Wiley.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>De Quervain, D. J. -F., Fischbacher, U., Treyer, V., Schellhammer, M., Schnyder, U., Buck, A., &amp;amp; Fehr, E (2004). The neural basis of altruistic punishment. Science, 305, 1254–1258.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Duffett, A., Johnson, J., &amp;amp; Farkas, S. Kids these days 99: What Americans really think about the next generation. Retrieved December 31, 2003 from &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.publicagenda.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>www.publicagenda.org&lt;/a>
Eisenberg, N., &amp;amp; Fabes, R. A. (1998). Prosocial development. In W. Damon (Series Ed.) N. Eisenberg (Volume Ed.), Handbook of child psychology, Vol. 3: Social, emotional, and personality development (5th ed., pp. 701–778). New York: John Wiley.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fabes, R. A., Carlo, G., Kupanoff, K., &amp;amp; Laible, D. J. (1999). Early adolescence and prosocial/ moral behavior I: The role of individual processes. Journal of Early Adolescence, 19, 5–16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart, D., &amp;amp; Carlo, G. (2005). Moral Development in Adolescence. Journal of Research on Adolescence (Wiley-Blackwell), 15(3), 223–233. &lt;a class="link" href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-7795.2005.00094.x" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-7795.2005.00094.x&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hart, D., Atkins, R., Markey, P., &amp;amp; Youniss, J. (2004). Youth bulges in communities: The effects of age structure on adolescent civic knowledge and civic participation. Psychological Science, 15, 591–597.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haynie, D., &amp;amp; Osgood, D. (2005). Reconsidering Peers and Delinquency: How do Peers Matter? Social Forces, 84(2), 1109-1130. Retrieved December 18, 2020, from &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/3598492" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.jstor.org/stable/3598492&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>James, W. (1890). The principles of psychology. New York: Holt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lawford, H., Pratt, M. W. &amp;amp; Arnold, M. L. (2009). Growing toward care: A narrative approach to prosocial moral identity and generativity of personality in emerging adulthood. In D. Narvaez &amp;amp; D. K. Lapsley (Eds.), Personality, identity, and character: Explorations in moral psychology (p. 295–315). Cambridge University Press. &lt;a class="link" href="https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511627125.014" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511627125.014&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Schepers, D. (2017). Moral Development in Adolescence: A Test of Change and Influences in Context of Sat with German Panel Data. Contemporary Readings in Law &amp;amp; Social Justice, 9(1), 70–97. &lt;a class="link" href="https://doi.org/10.22381/CRLSJ9120175" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://doi.org/10.22381/CRLSJ9120175&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Smetana, J. G. &amp;amp; Killen, M. (2015). Origins and development of morality. In M. E. Lamb &amp;amp; R. M. Lerner (Eds.), Handbook of child psychology and developmental science: Socioemotional processes (p. 701–749). John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Inc. &lt;a class="link" href="https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118963418.childpsy317" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118963418.childpsy317&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whiting, B. B., &amp;amp; Edwards, C. P. (1988). Children of different worlds. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Feast of Gluttony, Desire and Death</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/2158.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Feast of Gluttony, Desire and Death" />&lt;h2 id="introduction">&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 1973, Ferreri’s La Grande Bouffe was officially screened at the Cannes Film Festival where it
stirred great outrage (Taillibert, 2002). Instantly after its projection, the film placed itself in a
tradition of controversial movies that transcend from their initial shock value into debate and
deliberation for decades to come.
Many questions come to mind when viewing Ferreri’s La Grande Bouffe; is it a jab at the
debauchery of the bourgeoisie? Is there any deeper meaning to this spectacle of vomit and
excrement? Or, is it a mere dark comedy with cheap overused gags?
Without doubt, La Grande Bouffe is a confusing experience for the watcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="video-wrapper">
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/usASQnTtaWA"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
>
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Through this article, I investigate La Grande Bouffe philosophically. As I engage on the task,
I will touch on three main sections: (I) the first is a reconstruction of movie’s plot along with
its criticism, (II) the second and more substantial will be a discussion of the movie’s
transgression, subversion and desecration of philosophical elements, (III) and finally the third
section joins my conclusion on the movie and argumentation on its heightened philosophical
significance over a sociological one.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;h2 id="section-i-reconstruction-of-the-movies-plot-and-criticism">&lt;strong>Section I: Reconstruction of the movie’s plot and criticism&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="the-bourgeois-protagonists">&lt;strong>The Bourgeois Protagonists&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The movie begins with each protagonist in his own respective element:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 167;
flex-basis: 402px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/ugo.jpg" data-size="564x336">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/ugo.jpg"
width="564"
height="336"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/ugo_hu49bb231318c2f7bec06dcedfc4fa9609_18093_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/ugo_hu49bb231318c2f7bec06dcedfc4fa9609_18093_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Ugo">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Ugo&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure> &lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 150;
flex-basis: 360px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/michel.jpg" data-size="1000x666">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/michel.jpg"
width="1000"
height="666"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/michel_huf65b6de282650ce1c6bb640adc2e967f_93972_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/michel_huf65b6de282650ce1c6bb640adc2e967f_93972_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Michel">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Michel&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ugo&lt;/strong>, restaurateur, owns “Le Biscuit a Soupe”. His strained relationship with his wife is
demonstrated in their bickering over him wanting to take his knives, recipes and jarred
goods on his trip.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Michel&lt;/strong>, TV director, has programmed four weeks of televised shows and is willing to, in
his own terms, “faire une bonne action” towards his daughter by giving her the keys to
his apartment; in his dialogue with her, he insistently dismisses paternal authority.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 137;
flex-basis: 330px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/marcello.jpg" data-size="500x363">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/marcello.jpg"
width="500"
height="363"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/marcello_hu7e213424b54064cf1241a7618d41d489_48191_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/marcello_hu7e213424b54064cf1241a7618d41d489_48191_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Marcello">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Marcello&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure> &lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 166;
flex-basis: 400px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/philippe.jpg" data-size="1200x720">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/philippe.jpg"
width="1200"
height="720"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/philippe_hud0258420e238dce57caf48f04e1f8fa7_200710_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/philippe_hud0258420e238dce57caf48f04e1f8fa7_200710_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Philippe">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Philippe&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Marcello&lt;/strong>, the airline pilot, is perhaps the most mysterious of them. We do not get to see
the condition of his household or his relationship dynamics. Instead, Marcello is only
seen in his workplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Philippe&lt;/strong>, the judge, is babied by his nanny Nicole into a borderline incestuous
relationship. He is fed, nagged and followed around by her. She performs a sexual act on
him; which she qualifies as a continuity of her constant loving, adoring and motherly
sacrifices for him, however Phillippe differs by saying to her: &amp;ldquo;You always violate me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="the-plot">&lt;strong>The Plot&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 79;
flex-basis: 190px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/cinemaposters.jpg" data-size="950x1200">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/cinemaposters.jpg"
width="950"
height="1200"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/cinemaposters_hu1bdd7d4735390ff47914db87e19665fb_242830_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/cinemaposters_hu1bdd7d4735390ff47914db87e19665fb_242830_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Marco Ferreri. La Grande Bouffe">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Marco Ferreri. La Grande Bouffe&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite their contrasting differences, the four characters have some commonalities. They all are
keeping their escapade secret, and they all carry gifts into their mission.
Ugo bears his culinary expertise, jars and knives, Michel brings cleaning utilities, Marcello imports cheese and packed
goods, and finally Philippe offers the setting for the rest of the movie: a manor in the chicest
district of Paris, in the street Boileau.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After being welcomed into the manor by Hector, an elderly handyman, their first day is marked
by a visit from a Chinese ambassador convoying purchasing the mansion, excessively grandiose
meat and vegetable deliveries, and long preparations. Both Michel and Marcello interact with
statuettes of women; Michel dusts then whips one with his glove inside the manor, while
Marcello caresses perversely a statue in the garden. At dinner time, oysters are devoured at a
frenetic pace by the four protagonists while they observe nude photography of young women.
Ironically, Michel irritated and uncomfortable at the nudity points out: &amp;ldquo;We are not here to have a villainous orgy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the second day, Marcello expresses that he cannot only content himself with food: he needs
women, and for one thing: having sex. Soon, a charming bubbly institutor Andrea invites herself
along with her class to see the linden tree of Boileau, and then gets treated to delicious food.
Immediately, she catches the Judge’s eye and she is invited for dinner with the four friends and
three other eager sex workers. The dinner party is a debacle of food, nudity and sex, where
Andrea reveals herself to be quite promiscuous. Michel lapidates a prostitute’s body with food
while proclaiming repetitively: &amp;ldquo;The female body is a vanity&amp;rdquo;. Philippe announces his
engagement to Andrea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, the prostitutes forfeit one by one, expressing their disgust at the alimentary excesses
of their hosts &amp;ldquo;Do things other than eat, eat, always eat&amp;rdquo;. Michel starts to suffer
from congestion gas pains, but still is pressured to keep eating by his friends. Philippe
encourages him: &amp;ldquo;It is a question of will&amp;rdquo;, while Ugo reminds him of their now evident
suicide pact: “Eat again my little Michel, eat. If you don&amp;rsquo;t eat, you won&amp;rsquo;t pass away.&amp;quot;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrea chooses to stay; stating so with an eerie expression on her face. In the following scene,
she yells &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m hungry!!&amp;rdquo; which prompts the four friends right back on track. The feast ensues,
while their bodies start to break down; Michel is pained by violent flatulence, Ugo’s face is
rosaceous and Marcello becomes impotent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a moment of tension, Marcello breaks the fourth wall: “There is no fantasy in this story, they chose the crudest way to die”,
after which ultimately, with all the impetus of a crescendo, the toilets explode.
Later on in bed with his friends, Ugo proclaims: “The smell of shit will never leave us”, to which Michel answers: &amp;ldquo;The Universal Flood&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still covered in fecal matter, Marcello tries to leave, only to be found dead behind the wheel of
his beloved Bugatti. Michel follows and dies from an indigestion, Ugo gorges himself to death
on his best creation. Philippe succumbs to his diabetes after eating breast shaped flans. Each of
the four characters dies without dignity, nor the mercifulness of a proper burial.
The final meat delivery ends up being useless, excessive and is plainly wasted: thrown by the
butchers for the dogs to enjoy, while Andrea sorrowfully goes back to the manor.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Tldr;&lt;/strong> Four accomplished rich friends decide to die&amp;ndash; with the most basal of pleasurable ways: food.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="critique">&lt;strong>Critique&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="critic-1-jordan-white">&lt;em>&lt;strong>Critic 1: Jordan White&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>According to a critic in DVD classic by Jordan White, a forum for movie’ analysis and critics,
“La Grande Bouffe” is more than a simple comedy as it touches on passion, boredom, the midlife
crisis of the forties and loneliness. Ferreri flips off the sanctimonious by paving the way for
movies as iconic and as cult to be debated positively and negatively. White states that Marco
Ferreri’s masterpiece makes us chuckle by its comedic pitch, by the actor’s investiture and
dedication, but also by its ability to make us think (White, 2006).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="critic-2-taillibert">&lt;em>&lt;strong>Critic 2: Taillibert&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In Taillibert’s cinematic review, she theorizes that a serious diabetes crisis might have been a
potential source for Ferreri’s cinematographic inspiration. However, she also finds that that the
vices and weaknesses of the bourgeoisie had caught Ferreri’s attention and alternately led his wrath
against the insolent opulence of capitalist societies, collective alienations, the Catholic
Church, money and power; in which Ferreri’s cinematographic revolt was ultimately
accomplished through food and sex, two elements that society places at the top ladder of pleasure.
Tallibert also discusses the newsroom’s reaction and inexhaustible surge of insults for the
filmmaker. For some, it&amp;rsquo;s the vulgarity of the film that is in cause, others reproached him the
nihilistic foundations by putting forth humanistic values, while others hid behind the religious
values of Christian morality. She concludes by stating that film’s like La Grande Bouffe are,
after all, excellent tools to dissect the vices of modern society; quoting Michel Piccoli’s
interview with Serge Toubiania on La Grande Bouffe in a special supplement of the Cahiers du
cinema : « (…) comme si Marco nous ouvrait et nous montrait notre cancer » (Taillibert, 2002).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="critic-3-christine-lahaie">&lt;em>&lt;strong>Critic 3: Christine Lahaie&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In the article « De Quelques Films Culinaires » by Christiane Lahaie, she states that “La Grande
Bouffe” makes us reconcile with our nature as omnivores. Marco Ferrerri initiated a starter for a
succession of movies in which consumption of food create the dramatic note like “Le Cuisinier,
le voleur, Sa Femme et son Amant” by Peter Greenway. But none will ever attain the same level
of abjection by linking food and death. However, she finds that the movie betrays misogynistic
ideals through the character of Andrea as a helper of death and desire, and that is unaffected by
an incessant gluttonous gurgitation of food. Lahaie sees La Grande Bouffe’s feasting as a
catalyser of a deviant sexuality where food is a compensator for the repression of religion, fear of
others and self-narcissism. (Lahaie, 2002)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="section-ii-discussion-transgression-subversion-and-desecration-of-philosophical-elements">&lt;strong>Section II: Discussion: Transgression, Subversion and Desecration of Philosophical Elements&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 166;
flex-basis: 400px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/andrea.jpg" data-size="1200x720">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/andrea.jpg"
width="1200"
height="720"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/andrea_hu4fc2b0463719360417228791a455393d_242004_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/andrea_hu4fc2b0463719360417228791a455393d_242004_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Andrea, the symbolism of Transgression, Subversion and Desecration">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Andrea, the symbolism of Transgression, Subversion and Desecration&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the movie, the four friends behaved in an opposite manner of what the
ancient philosopher, Plato, commends.
Plato&amp;rsquo;s philosophy consists of the belief that the world is a reflection of a truer reality, and that in order to philosophize
freely and attain knowledge, humans need to get rid of distraction and distortions.
There are three main prohibited distractions that are encouraged in the movie: excess and gluttony, sex and art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters subvert and transgress those elements: bodily pleasures, food and art are used as a distraction.
They exceed the necessity and at some point; they affect the characters talents and
diminishes their capacity to operate.
An example of that is Ugo, an acclaimed the chef, who progressively gets worse at cooking or Michel who at first plays the piano smoothly and then
gradually becomes worse by forgetting notes and so.
Additionally, Plato considers art as speaking more to the heart than the mind and that it always is a copy of a copy.
He also criticizes all types of corporeal pleasures if not attained through love as a stairway to observe beauty.
The mansion was full of statues and representations: Marcello gropes perversely the statue in the garden and also uses an object to excite the blonde prostitute. In a way, the narrative of the movie is a subversion of Plato’s philosophy that considers the body and its pleasures as impediments from intellectual freedoms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cynic philosophy sees the good life as achieved by following nature: pursuing natural instinct,
manifested in simplicity, before social conventions and obligations. La Grande Bouffe desecrates
that teaching by following natural instincts by using excesses birthed through modernism,
conventions and obligations: the eccentricities and sophistication of the food, the decor and the
prostitutes. As for Rousseau, he described meat-eating as one of the cruelties of the modern
times, this idea can be seen as desecrated in the movie because the characters are overconsuming
all kinds of meat and in the end the carcasses of animals are thrown to be eaten by animals:
Rousseau considers meat-eating as “animals eating animals”. He prescribes eating normal food
and vegetables and he claims that “everything that is beyond necessity is a source of evil”.
Schopenhauer claims that there is a fourth way to be liberated from the will which is death by
suicide, but isn’t a solution to act on it because it is considered as a trick of the will since we are
wishing for a better life and end of misery, and since we are no longer alive to “Enjoy the Show”
unless death comes from slow starvation which is not considered a force of the will.
The characters subvert that teaching by doing the opposite of what Schopenhauer claims: instead they
eat themselves to death, which is not acceptable by him because they still “will to die” and
haven’t lost their will as they would have in self-starvation from an extreme ascetic life.
Schopenhauer also compares the will-of-life to music; Michel’s deteriorating musical capacities
might metaphorically be a way of showing the mortification of the will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epicurean philosophy encourages a materialistic view of pain which sees it is not a thing to fear:
major pain brings death and therefore deliverance from it, and generally encourages intellectual
pleasures after the pleasures of needs fulfilled, and generally favors the natural and necessary
pleasures over the non-natural and non-necessary ones. The latter is desecrated in the movie as
the protagonists indulge in natural and the necessary pleasures and needs to an extreme beyond
necessity and nature: gluttony and lechery. Lucretius conceptualizes sex and food as both
fulfilling, but food will always surpass sex as it can be absorbed by our bodies and therefore is
definitively more satisfying. This teaching is respected by the majority of the characters for the
most part, except for a few transgressions made by Marcello and Andrea who equally seek food
and sex and hold them to the same footing. It was Marcello’s idea to invite the prostitutes,
because the satisfaction of food is not enough and fulfilling enough for him, he needs sex too.
Ultimately, his breaking point is also directly related to him becoming impotent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="section-iii-general-conclusion">&lt;strong>Section III: General Conclusion&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To conclude, my verdict on La Grande Bouffe is that as preposterous and vulgar it might be: it
is purposeful in, at the very least, reflecting the philosophical absurdity of human nature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The movie can be observed as a fable about desires. But, of no fable was it more rightfully said:
it is unique in its linkage between death and desire. In its era, La Grande Bouffe dealt with a
specific desire that almost no film director had ever dared to approach before; the desire of humans to
die. The death drive, as originally coined by Sabrina Spielrein in 1912 and later expanded on in
Freudian psychanalysis, is defined as the inclination of humans towards death and self-destruction (Spielrein, 1995).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 160;
flex-basis: 384px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/freud.jpeg" data-size="1720x1075">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/freud.jpeg"
width="1720"
height="1075"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/freud_hub24fc897405f016dc2dd63f50dcf0b19_343406_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/freud_hub24fc897405f016dc2dd63f50dcf0b19_343406_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sigmund Freud in his study at Berggasse 19 in Vienna, 1934. (Freud Museum London)">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Sigmund Freud in his study at Berggasse 19 in Vienna, 1934. (Freud Museum London)&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Sigmund Freud, the death drive, Thanatos, is the antithesis of Eros, which is construed as the impulse
towards sex and survivalist instincts. Freud theorizes that all living beings have a desire or an instinct towards death (Cherry, 2019).
From a philosophical standpoint, the concept of the death drive aligns with Schopenhauer’s view of life’s aim as death,
as he considers existence itself as a continuum of dying and that completion is attained through it
(Encyclopedia of Death and Dying, n.d.).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although in my opinion, &lt;strong>sex and death can work as reciprocals rather than opposites&lt;/strong>. Both are
uncomfortable and difficult to talk about. It is common to live in denial of death, just as it is to
live in denial of our sexual desires. It takes ‘liberation’ to be open about sex, and ‘guts’ to accept
death. Perhaps, to incite liberation by gutting the viewer is one of the purposes of Ferreri’s
masterpiece.
Sex and death are reciprocal reminders of our animalistic nature.
Despite our efforts for distinction and sophistication or our inflated pride about human intellect; we remain animals regulated by the forces of nature.
La Grande Bouffe is emblematic in admonishing the audience of that by celebrating of the body being reduced to its most animalistic functions:
defecating, urinating, copulating, eating, gaging, regurgitating, inflating and dying (Celluloid
Liberation Front, 2014). Over and over in the movie, the audience can pick up on those reminders.
Marcello, the eccentric fashionable aviator, is hung in the freezer with beef carcasses, just like Michel.
Ugo passes on the counter of the kitchen; his cadaver posed as the final piece-de-resistance of his cuisine.
After being served dessert, the judge’s corpse is left amongst the meat in the garden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Their humanity is reduced to physiology, with their bodies typified as the flesh of animals; meat they gorged themselves upon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco Ferreri used provocation as a dynamic to represent a life without challenge and where all
pleasures are attained; the life of the bourgeois. Our bourgeois protagonists lead a painstakingly
monotone and boring life until they decide to end their lives: ironically, with too much appetite
for life.
Throughout the movie, it is hinted that our main four characters want to die until they blatantly admit to their suicide pact.
They do not kill themselves pro-actively, but rather seek it passively as a result of their destructive overindulgence.
The protagonists want to blissfully eat themselves to death. Ultimately, their pursuit of death is sought by what regulates life: food.
Lack of food, just as excess of food, leads to suffering and death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrea’s character assembles both food and sex. She is the insatiable metaphorical ogress of La Grande Bouffe’s fable; the
young woman opens herself to a universe she didn’t think she was able to make hers, and thus
liberates herself to unleash her insatiable appetite for lechery and gluttony. Andrea also becomes
as sort of anti-mother; she offers the maternal tenderness by being kind and infantilizing the
names of the four protagonists, but she is not a mother that births, rather than that she is a mother
that guides them to death. Thus, the symbolization of the drive of death, sex and food is taken to
its extreme to serve us, the audience; &lt;strong>a feast of gluttony, desire and sex&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The heightened philosophical importance of the movie over its sociological one is evident in that
symbolization. The movie has some sociological facets: it openly scandalizes a consumerist
elitist bourgeois class, perhaps on the basis of received ideas and stereotypes on the bourgeoisie
in its time. Yet observing it only as primarily sociological limits its range: it targets only a
stereotyped bourgeois class and their pursuit of death can be just passed as an extravagance and
indulgence. On the other hand, accosting La Grande Bouffe as a philosophical movie is much
more interesting; it gains much more meaning as it can relate, more broadly, to the philosophy of
human nature, the meaninglessness of life, the pursuit of pleasure, absurdism and of most
relevantly to our class: food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, it is important to point out La Grande Bouffe has pushed audiences and critics to search
for meaning in its meaninglessness as if to make an absurdist point; a majority of secondary
characters and events seem to have no plot relevancy to the story or the character development,
yet these characters and those events simply exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="section-iv-bibliography">&lt;strong>Section IV: Bibliography&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Celluloid Liberation Front. (2014, March 25). Consumerist Ultimate Indigestion: La Grande
Bouffe&amp;rsquo;s Deadly Physiological Pleasures.
Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="https://brightlightsfilm.com/consumerist-ultimate-indigestion-la-grande-bouffes-deadly-physiological-pleasures/#.Xd73t-j7RPY" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://brightlightsfilm.com/consumerist-ultimate-indigestion-la-grande-bouffes-deadly-physiological-pleasures/#.Xd73t-j7RPY&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cherry, K. (2019, June 27). How Life and Death Instincts Are Opposing Urges.
Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.verywellmind.com/life-and-death-instincts-2795847" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.verywellmind.com/life-and-death-instincts-2795847&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Encyclopedia of Death and Dying. (n.d.). Schopenhauer, Arthur.
Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.deathreference.com/Py-Se/Schopenhauer-Arthur.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.deathreference.com/Py-Se/Schopenhauer-Arthur.html&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lahaie, C. (2002). De quelques films culinaires : entre Éros et Thanatos. Québec français (126),
55–57. URI: &lt;a class="link" href="https://id.erudit.org/iderudit/55841ac" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://id.erudit.org/iderudit/55841ac&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spielrein, S. (1995). &amp;ldquo;Destruction as cause of becoming&amp;rdquo; by Sabina Spielrein, M.D.
Psychoanalysis &amp;amp; Contemporary Thought, 18(1), 85–118.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taillibert, C. (2002). La grande bouffe (Marco Ferreri 1973). Cinemaction; Filméditions; Corlet,
1-6. HAL Id : halshs-02190551, version 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>White, J. (2006, February 9). Critique De Film - La Grande bouffe.
Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.dvdclassik.com/critique/la-grande-bouffe-ferreri?fbclid=IwAR3vxrBrfaJFAxSInrh5LI7MPgynkiKT4tKlWTV6_HFRbPx3NGyqTSSp1oM" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.dvdclassik.com/critique/la-grande-bouffe-ferreri?fbclid=IwAR3vxrBrfaJFAxSInrh5LI7MPgynkiKT4tKlWTV6_HFRbPx3NGyqTSSp1oM&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sidi Ali ben Hemdouch: Social and Religious Dynamics in Morocco</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Sidi Ali ben Hemdouch: Social and Religious Dynamics in Morocco" />&lt;h2 id="who-is-khalid-mouna">Who is Khalid Mouna?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dr. Khalid Mouna is an anthropologist, professor of sociology at Moulay Ismail University in Meknes. His research publications focus on cannabis, social mobilization and migration. Dr. Mouna’s article, “Le corps à l&amp;rsquo;épreuve du &amp;ldquo;sacré&amp;rdquo;: le rituel du corps à Sidi Ali Ben Hamdouch au Maroc”, delves into the fundamental relationship between social and religious dynamics in Morocco. He studied Sidi Ali ben Hemdouch as a social laboratory to study the construction of sainthood, sacred spaces and the therapeutic power of “L’baraka” or spiritual blessings. His research was for the most-part observational and exploratory, with the exception of twenty semi-structured interviews aimed at unifying diverse myths surrounding the role and sainthood of Lalla Aicha; as the orality surrounding her reflects the inversion of gender roles, L’baraka and chains of power. In this post, I reflect on some of the ideas in his article.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-scene-of-sidi-ali-ben-hemdouch">The Scene of Sidi Ali Ben Hemdouch&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 177;
flex-basis: 426px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali3.jpg" data-size="1280x720">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali3.jpg"
width="1280"
height="720"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali3_huc07d6820e347aad1d9511c94893d7d67_221327_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali3_huc07d6820e347aad1d9511c94893d7d67_221327_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sidi Ali Ben Hmdouch">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Sidi Ali Ben Hmdouch&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidi Ali Ben Hamdouch is a small town in the semi-mountainous region on the heights of Zerhoun, near Meknes.
After each Mawlid commemoration, the locals erect a sanctuary that bubbles the day with Sufi vigils, chanting, sacrifices of chicken, sheep and cows and other folk songs performed by the “H’madcha” troops, guardians of the temple. The town lits up during the seven days of the Moussem, arrived from different localities, some from abroad, the pilgrims occupy night and day the mausoleum of the “Saint”, begging for his legendary blessing.
They light candles on a wall blackened with burns, sprinkle it with rose water, and bring baskets of dwarf palms filled with milk, henna, incense and bread. A whole procession improvised by these pilgrims who, powdering their faces white, introduce their offerings (H’diya) reminiscent of the traditional wedding ceremonies.
&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 160;
flex-basis: 384px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali.png" data-size="781x487">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali.png"
width="781"
height="487"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali_hubaabe34f1ff95cdec7007d384cd7052f_736089_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/sidiali_hubaabe34f1ff95cdec7007d384cd7052f_736089_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Sacrifice of sheep during the Sidi Ali festival, January 21, 2014 in Sidi Ali, near Meknes, Morocco [Fedel Senna / AFP]">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>Sacrifice of sheep during the Sidi Ali festival, January 21, 2014 in Sidi Ali, near Meknes, Morocco [Fedel Senna / AFP]&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
Dr. Mouna considers Sidi Ali as proof of a broken barrier between a popular Islam and an official scholarly Islam in Morocco. Through his argumentation, he successfully evokes and contextualizes the myths of Lalla Aicha Al Hmdouchia, Sidi Ali and Sidi Ahmed socially by establishing a link between spiritual healing rituals and Moroccan lore; as he defines myths as subscribing to a partial reality involved in social, cultural and religious dynamics transmitted from generation to generation, and most importantly as a way of legitimizing power.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-origins">The origins&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>According to some of Dr. Mouna’s sources, Sidi Ali first arrived in the village of Beni Rached as a lost traveler, where he founded a Zawya and then proceeded to birth himself as a saint by performing a miracle; the one of life. He had helped the young wife of the Sultan Moulay Ismail conceive after much difficulty, and the Sultan after learning of his miracle had honored Sidi Ali by the construction of mausoleum to establish him as a saint to be revered. Another myth places Sidi Ali as the mqaddem of the Sultan and as one capable of cursing others into blindness and sickness for mystical ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other important figure, Sidi Ahmed Dghoughi wanted to be a servant and disciple of Sidi Ali and was promised the same Baraka if he prepared him water of his ablutions and brought him back the wife of his choosing: a princess of Sudan; Aisha the daughter of King Ol Khir. Sidi Ahmed took on the quest and travelled to Sudan to bring the bride, only to be find out at his return the unfortunate news of his master’s demise. Sidi Ahmed could not bear the news; he broke down and stabled the beginning of what would be known as the Hmdouchi rite: he hacked his head with an ax and hayed Allah. Aicha disappears with the news of the death of Sidi Ali.
During the talk in the class, Dr. Mouna evocated a myth which placed Lalla Aicha as dotted with the power of shapeshifting into the opposite sex. In this context, without the protection of either Sidi Ali and Sidi Ahmed, she becomes vulnerable to the most wicked intent of the villagers. To escape getting violated by a horde of men, she shapeshifts into a man, but to her dismay she still is violated.
Angered and aggravated, Aicha goes on to become this vengeful spirit against men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, stories surrounding the three figures imply sexual inversion. The sexual proximity between Sidi Ahmed and Sidi Ali is heavily implied; such as that Sidi Ali is considered as the patron of homosexual men, or as stated in the article the patron of the derogatory term ‘zwamal’, and Aicha as this spiritual figure working hand in hand with the saint to protect the patronized. The apparition of Lalla Aicha as a spiritual figure decentralized sainthood and allowed for a flight line to acquire L’baraka without being honored or genealogically affiliated to a saint; Lalla Aicha allowed for the feminization of sainthood and honor. Unlike the two saints Sidi Ahmed and Sidi Ali who are restricted to their sanctuaries, Lalla Aicha is an omnipresent being and appears as half djinyia half human with her beauty as an indication of her humanity and her hooved feet of her inhuman mystical presence. To ask for Aicha’s powers to get what one seeks, they must wholeheartedly believe in her power and erase any drop of doubt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The descent of Sidi Ali is irrigated by the lineage of his brother, that allows for the chowaf/a to present a strong case against the charaf passed on genealogically. The arrival of the chowaf to the village is due to economic interests and spiritual curiosity. Most of the Hmadcha are not native to the region; they migrated due to economic reasons. To become a chowaf of Lalla Aicha is an individual experience ingrained in encounter with her, sufferings, and finally a blessing in being allowed to occupy the position by her. Taking the case of Rachid; the apprentice chowaf is a frequent visitor of Sidi Ali to venerate Lalla Aicha. He describes himself as inhabited by the spirit: he describes feeling possessed and monopolized by her; in the way that she possessively keeps him from getting married but provides him with money, revenge against his enemies, and tortures him by making him self-harm when he disobeys her or neglects her sacrifices and venerations. The second interlocutor of Dr. Mouna; Hamid also describes himself as inhabited by Aicha and he says that he established a successful pact with her. Through rituals involving effeminates and girls, he blesses clients with his Baraka who in exchange offer money. Dr. Mouna stated in the class that those rituals are also entertained by the bourgeoisie. The rites attached to Aicha can be used for both bad and good intent; taking the example of “T’qaf” for instance which can be used for the protection of the girl from rape, or to curse a couple into sexual dysfunction; either vaginismus or erectile dysfunction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The power of Aicha causes much concern to the effeminates as it makes them feel out of place from their orthodox Islamic beliefs, which consider placing anyone above Allah in terms of granting prayers or wishes as blasphemy. The effeminate chowaf’s body serves as a vessel for Aicha, and inversely it allows for them to exist in a society that admonishes homosexual men. She holds an androgenic position with helped establish a duality to unify between the effeminates; they are neither totally men nor totally women.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="acceptance-through-lore-and-myths">Acceptance through lore and myths&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In light of Dr. Mouna’s research, we can observe how Moroccan lore and myths have created acceptance for individuals ostracized in a society dominated by orthodox Islam. Non-binary and gender non-conforming individuals or in Dr. Mouna’s terms “effeminates” find a respite in their identity through Aicha; they can embrace androgenetic qualities under her cover, and even acquire social power as well as approval through that identity.
Homosexuality is also relativized in a popular Islam by spirit inhabitance or possession; it is normalized and even ‘excused’ as an uncontrollable behavior that the possessed person did not choose, comparatively the same as saying “born that way”, and facilitates seeing it as than a result of a rather mystical concept: supernatural behavior rather than both nature and nurture. Therefore, the urgency to sanction those individuals for their identity or sexuality in Islam is lifted as its identifiers are seen through the lens of spirit possession as victims and not as sinners or perpetrators of a religious calamity. Lalla Aicha is in sorts the beard of those individuals, and their protector from a greater tormentor than her: society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although the lore of sorcery and sainthood in Morocco can be beneficial to helping those individuals placate an identity and bypass rigid religious dynamics, the entire folk culture of sorcery and saint related practices is problematic. It is heavily frowned upon and is plagued with the quackery of individuals who prey on the desperation and gullibility of people. It can lead to overlooking serious mental illnesses and physiological disorders: more so it standardizes mental illness, like schizoid disorders, as djinn possessions and physiological illness, such as cancer, as the wrath of a djinn. It can easily misguide people from getting medical treatment, and lead their families into financial exploitation by requiring simply greater sacrifices or money when a spiritual treatment fails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Likewise, it is socially taxing to indulge into sorcery or venerate sainthoods within Morocco: for instance, it is considered a valid ground for divorce and for cutting familial ties. To my knowledge, Morocco amassed an increasing bad reputation abroad because of sorcery and saint practices: it is understandable due to some of those practices being morbid and involving poisoning others “T’ewkal”, blood sacrifices, self-harm and using human body parts through grave scavenging.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To conclude, Dr. Mouna&amp;rsquo;s article was an interesting perspective on the context in which non-heteronormative individuals were able to co-exist with a conservative Muslim society, and to contextualize themselves within it. However, it overlooks the fact that the entire folk culture of sorcery in Morocco is disapproved of and that although those individuals might gain the acceptance of some part of the population; that population would be in the rebuked minority that believes in entertaining those rites and practices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/steve-harvey-asSl-LZQCdU-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti" />&lt;h2 id="context-and-setting">Context and Setting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As an aftermath of World War II, an intense economic and military struggle wedged itself between two superpowers: the Soviet Union and the United States. A political and ideological rivalry ensued for decades and marked a period that became known as the Cold War; a term coined by Truman’s political consultant, Bernard Barruch. It was a time was characterized by a series of proxy wars, competitions, atomic and scientific races between the Soviets and the Americans and no direct confrontation. Although it marked a period of fearfulness and economic crisis; it was one of most decisive period in the 20th century and served as an incubator for modern science. Without the context of the Cold War, many revolutionizing inventions wouldn’t have occurred. We owe it the internet, satellites, phone calls and modern computers. Due to it, the space race officially begun; most pointedly when the first satellite Sputnik 1 was launched by the USSR in 1957. While in the US, the ancestor of current internet ARPANET was first funded in 1966 and was the first network to introduce TCP/IP protocols on which modern internet is based. Technological warfare advances were also phenomenal in regard to bombers, lasers and nuclear programs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The enmity between the USSR and Western powers like France, Britain and the US was first delineated in Russia’s hindrance of plans to rebuild Germany economically. Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin, head of the Soviet Union in the 40s, was convinced that the economic restoration plans of Europe served as means of snatching away Eastern bloc countries from Russia’s grip and weakening its economy. Many operatives and schemes were conducted to counter such plans. One of the most notorious Soviet operative is the 1948 Czech coup d’état in which communists led street brutality, took over the law enforcement sector and forced the president to resign or face civil war. Soon after it, the Berlin blockade was established in June 1948 was one of the first tipping points of the Cold War. West-Berlin was sieged by the Soviet Union and deprived from supplies and food while East-Berlin was controlled by it. The Berlin airlift initiative taken by many developed countries began to provide West-Berlin with approximately 8,800 tons of supplies daily (Nash, 2008).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result from the escalation of the tension, eleven countries along with the United States established NATO in 1949, short for North Atlantic Treaty Organization, whose primary purpose was to unify and build up forces in the eventuality of an attack by USSR and its allies and a third world war. The United States worked towards disbanding communist influences by backing financially the nationalist countermovement to communism in China and Korea. Many proxy wars between the superpowers followed suit in China and Korea while alliances were formed in Japan, Australia and other countries. The rivalry of the Soviets and Americans was pointedly rooted to the USA’s use of nuclear weapons on Japan during World War II. The leaders of the USSR realized the threat of Atomic bombs and began developing their own. As soon as the Soviet Union detonated its first state-of-the-art Plutonium bomb RDS-1 august 1949 as a test; Western powers detected it and were aghast. Their intelligence had underestimated Russia’s Atomic programs (Aldrich, 1998).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, the strain between the US and Russia was heightened by their two different contradictory economic systems. The United States were and still are a capitalist nation basing itself on private ownership, uneven distribution of wealth and competitive markets. The Soviet Union was in its essence a communist regime that adopted a totalitarian government and equal distribution of wealth. Americans criticized the USSR because its communist system and ideology was considered a threat to liberty for its suppression of individual rights, censorship and totalitarianism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;figure
class="gallery-image"
style="
flex-grow: 79;
flex-basis: 189px"
>
&lt;a href="https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/library-of-congress-R2WAxzVBxxo-unsplash.jpg" data-size="2400x3036">
&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/library-of-congress-R2WAxzVBxxo-unsplash.jpg"
width="2400"
height="3036"
srcset="https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/library-of-congress-R2WAxzVBxxo-unsplash_hu0d0f6effedf39efb4bdfc6777df4f4df_920188_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/library-of-congress-R2WAxzVBxxo-unsplash_hu0d0f6effedf39efb4bdfc6777df4f4df_920188_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="[Harry Truman, half-length portrait, facing front]. Photograph from the Presidential File Collection, c1945. Library of Congress Prints &amp; Photographs Division. https://www.loc.gov/item/96523444/">
&lt;/a>
&lt;figcaption>[Harry Truman, half-length portrait, facing front]. Photograph from the Presidential File Collection, c1945. Library of Congress Prints &amp;amp; Photographs Division. &lt;a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/96523444/">https://www.loc.gov/item/96523444/&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Quoting President Truman “The seeds of totalitarian regimes are nurtured by misery and want” (The Truman Doctrine, delivered 12 March 1947 before a Joint Session of Congress).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Soviets were also not keen America for its capitalistic system rendering it inherently unscrupulous and guilty of creating economic inequality. Both nation recurred to political expediency and criticism of each other to vindicate for military expenditures, and ferociously fought for influence all over the globe to gain allies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1953 marked a major shift in the dynamics of the Cold War. Truman left office after finishing his term length, and Stalin, who was most likely murdered, passed away from a cerebral hemorrhage. Eisenhower was inaugurated as president of the US. All the while, the Soviet Union was in a state of jeopardy. Stalin’s death sparked off power struggles between political aspirants. Lavrentiy Pavlovich Beria, an influential chief of secret police and deputy head of the People’s Commissariat for Internal Affairs under Stalin, was briefly elevated to First deputy Premier in 1953 before being overthrown and arrested during a coup d’état by his soviet political rivals.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-formation-of-the-kgb">The Formation of the KGB&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The arrest and trial revealed Beria’s true horrid sadistic nature. He was found guilty of treason, terrorism, abuse of power and counter-revolutionary activity along with many accounts of sexual predation, sexual extortion and brutal rapes on young girls. Later evidence found several corpses of women buried in the garden of Beria’s Moscow villa (Sixsmith, 2011). Lavrentiy Beria rule was marked by him merging the Ministry of State security MGB into the Ministry of Internal Affairs MVD as one working body, and with much difficulty trying to lead a more liberalizing regime by signing decrees to end prison torture. Although he was not a bad ruler as Russia’s Premier, Beria’s legacy forever suffered from his gruesome crimes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With his execution, the newly formed Ministry of internal affairs was dissolved. Soon thereafter a Soviet statesman, Nikita Khrushchev was assigned as Premier of the Soviet Union. The USSR entered a phase of secretive de-Stalinization. The MGB was re-formed to retain its previous powers and a new agency was formed: the KGB. The KGB stands for “Komitet gosudarstvennoy bezopasnosti” which is Russian for the Committee of State security. It was founded on Marth 13th 1954 by the Presidium of the Supreme Soviet with the symbolic emblem of the sword and the shield. Unlike any other intelligence of that time, the KGB worked as an independent government body with as minimal handling as possible by political leaders of the USSR and directed Russia’s secret police as well as domestic surveillance units. It excelled at information-gathering operatives to the extent that it was reported as the world’s most effective espionage intelligence in a Time’s article by John Kohan (Kohan, 1983).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The KGB was tasked with conducting political espionage, military infiltration, economic sabotage and technology acquisition missions in target countries by either legal or illegal spies. There were two classes of spies: agents and controllers. The legal agents were Soviet citizens permitted to reside in target countries by a way of working in consulates or embassies. They were protected from prosecution by political immunity if caught red-handed or repatriated if compromised. Although riskier, the illegal spies were more fruitful because they were able to integrate society without raising immediate suspicion. These spies led a double life by masking themselves under an assumed identity. The controllers are the ones who relay the instruction and work towards ensuring the success of the mission. The organization recruited civilians dedicated to the communist cause or forcefully by blackmailing them. These undercover contacts ranked from high placed intellectuals to common folk. Internally, the KGB inspired a sentiment of fear because of it imprisonment, torture and assassination of political dissidents. Soviet critics of the communist systems were confined in psychiatric institutions for indeterminate periods (British Medical Association, 1992). It had surveillance departments that monitored unauthorized media, religious activity and Soviet Jews. The spy agency investigated and sabotaged political leaders that threatened the stability of the Soviet Union. A rough estimate found that the KGB had approximately eleven million informers during its entire existence (Pringle, 2000).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The majority of the illegal undercover KGB agents were located in the United States and wrought to infiltrate, subvert and placate on all levels of American society. Some of their spies had already infiltrated America before the Cold War as part of other operations, while others were smuggled from the Soviet embassy in Canada and given fake identity and narratives. Although it is important to note that even if illegal infiltrations were preferred, legal infiltrations were more successful by a large margin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, infiltrators in the Middle East outdid themselves in promoting dissent to destabilize allies of the US and most specifically: Israel. These agent provocateurs trained, strengthened and armed the Palestine Liberation Organization to conduct guerilla attacks and terroristic acts such as the Avivim school bus massacre which killed nine children and crippled nineteen others in 1970, multiple plane hijackings in the 60s and coastal road massacres in 1978. Aleksandr Sakharovsky, Soviet General and First Chief Directorate of the KGB in 1955, was quoted to have said: “Airplane hijacking is my own invention” and considered the hijacking of Israeli airplanes as an intelligence success. Yuri Vladimirovich Andropov, a Soviet politician and KGB chairman, pressed that by hammering the idea that the United States and Israel were the embodiment of Zionist fascist imperialism financed by Jewish bankrolls terrorist violence would flow from Islamic fervor (Papeca, 2006).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Soviet regime was publicly supporting and sponsoring the PLO (Spector, 1969). Controversially, the Palestine Liberation Organization was found in a 1993 report by Britain’s NCIS to be the wealthiest terrorist group with an annual income of two billion dollars and around 10 billion dollars in possessions (Baracskay, 2011). Starting the 60s, Russia was actively using the KGB to sear Nazi-style hatred against the United States and Israel throughout the Islamic world by manipulating ancestral abhorrence for Judaism. By 1978, the entire Soviet intelligences are estimated to have deployed four thousand influencers in the Arab world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Allegedly, the KGB was said to have engaged in arming the terrorist Official Irish Republican Army to commit attacks that killed over thirty-six thousand people. The reason being to distend internal diplomatic affairs with England and to encourage the IRA into turning Ireland into a communist regime. Conspiracy theories and fake propaganda were commonly used to sabotage a nation. The most famous circulated piece of propaganda during the Cold War was that the American government had deliberately infected homosexual and African Americans with HIV and AIDS during vaccinations as a mean of racial genocide in 1980. It was published in pro-Soviet journals endorsing the medical opinion of a professor and theorizing that it was first tried on inmates in exchange of an early release. When the Cold War came to an end, former KGB agent Vasili Mitrokhin discredited the theory by declaring that it was part of an operative called “Operation INFEKTION” (Andrew &amp;amp; Mitrokhin, 1999).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The KGB was renowned for its lethal reputation. Testimonies of defected ex-KGB agents reveal the Soviet prowess for assassination techniques. Bohdan Stashynsky testified of Lev Rebet’s cunning assassination. Rebet was a Ukrainian nationalist and an outspoken anti-communist. Lev’s first autopsy showed that he had passed away from a heart attack while in truth he had been neutralized by a KGB agent with a vapor gun that puffed a cloud of odorless cyanide gas. Former citizens and defectors of the Soviet regime were a source of concern for the USSR and they sought out murdering them. The use of toxins or chemical compounds by Soviet intelligence is inconsistent to complicate diagnosis and tracking (Central Intelligence Agency, 2011). Oftentimes, KGB spies retorted to seduction techniques to set honey traps for their victims. Seductresses were called swallows, while seducers ravens (Payne, 1984). Victims were lured in apartments by attractive young women to be recorded and then blackmailed. Amusingly, even though the Soviet Union often recurs to blackmailing; it has no tolerance for it. In the case of a hostage situation of four Soviet diplomats by the Hezbollah in 1985, the KGB was not pleased and instead of engaging in careful negotiations: they tracked down a relative of the Hezbollah leader to castrate, torture and then send his dismembered body parts of the captors along with notes containing names of other family members of the terrorists. As a result, the Hezbollah let go of the diplomats unharmed immediately (The Guardian, 1986).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The efforts of the KGB and other intelligence services were fruitful into maintain the Iron Curtain between the allies of the Soviet Union and members of the NATO. Nonetheless, the Soviet Union was crumpling mostly because of economic stagnation and incentives due to its lack of competitive free markets. Nationalism in republics of the USSR was accentuated by ethnic differences. Diplomacy between the Americans and the soviets had slowly improved over the years which led into a demotivation to sabotage them. Monocentric decision-making that barred discussions and incompetence of leaders. Prioritizing military and security forces above developing the economy. Heavy censorship that created brainwashed generations incapacitated of questioning authority. Committing crimes against humanity, especially in the Afghan war, and suffering from international diplomatic backlash. Army, secret police and KGB were weakened by multiple betrayals from defectors and denounced by ambitious local leaders of the republics of the USSR. Religion was settling in Russian society and adopted the Orthodox Church as the state religion. Yet, the primary reason the Soviet Union couldn’t be sustained is the ideology on which it was founded: its rendition of communism, which couldn&amp;rsquo;t be self-sustainable and led to economic failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following the dissolution of the USSR in 1991, the KGB was disbanded. A new domestic security service replaced it called the FSB and occupied its previous Moscow headquarters assuming partially some of the functions as its forerunner. The Cold War is said to have ended as diplomatic relations between the US and Russia have drastically improved in the late few years, even if the rumored involvement of the Russian government in Trump’s campaign has risen new allegations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was truly a fascinating period of history.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Aldrich, Richard J. (July 1998). &amp;ldquo;British Intelligence and the Anglo-American &amp;lsquo;Special Relationship&amp;rsquo; during the Cold War&amp;rdquo;. Review of International Studies. 24 (3): 331–351. doi: 10.1017/S0260210598003313. JSTOR 20097530.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Andrew, C. M., &amp;amp; Mitrokhin, V. (1999). The sword and the shield: The Mitrokhin archive and the secret history of the KGB. New York: Basic Books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>British Medical Association, Medicine betrayed: the participation of doctors in human rights abuses. Zed Books; 1992. ISBN 1-85649-104-8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Central Intelligence Agency, Soviet Use of Assassination and Kidnapping. (2011, August 04). Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.cia.gov/library/center-for-the-study-of-intelligence/kent-csi/vol19no3/html/v19i3a01p_0001.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.cia.gov/library/center-for-the-study-of-intelligence/kent-csi/vol19no3/html/v19i3a01p_0001.htm&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Kohan (14 February 1983). &amp;ldquo;Eyes of the Kremlin&amp;rdquo;. Retrieved n.d.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nash, Gary B. &amp;ldquo;The Next Steps: The Marshall Plan, NATO, and NSC-68.&amp;rdquo; The American People: Creating a Nation and a Society. New York: Pearson Longman, 2008. P 828.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pacepa, I. M. (2006, August 24). Russian Footprints. Retrieved July 6, 2018, from &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nationalreview.com/2006/08/russian-footprints-ion-mihai-pacepa/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.nationalreview.com/2006/08/russian-footprints-ion-mihai-pacepa/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robert W. Pringle. Andropov&amp;rsquo;s Counterintelligence State, International Journal of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, 13:2, 193–203, page 196, 2000&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ronald Payne, Christopher Dobson (1984). Who&amp;rsquo;s Who in Espionage? New York: St. Martin&amp;rsquo;s Press.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spector, Ivan, The Soviet Union and the Muslim world, 1917–1958, Seattle: University of Washington Press, 1969, p. 172.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Guardian (1986, January 07). KGB Reportedly Gave Arab Terrorists a Taste of Brutality to Free Diplomats. Retrieved from &lt;a class="link" href="http://articles.latimes.com/1986-01-07/news/mn-13892_1_soviets" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://articles.latimes.com/1986-01-07/news/mn-13892_1_soviets&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Palestine Liberation Organization: Terrorism and Prospects for Peace in the Holy Land, Daniel Baracskay, 2011, page 83, Prager Security International, ISBN 9780313381515&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Juvenoia</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/juvenoia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/juvenoia/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://computerwitch.me/post/juvenoia/emile-guillemot-Olo2khVaTmk-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Juvenoia" />&lt;div class="video-wrapper">
&lt;iframe loading="lazy"
src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LD0x7ho_IYc"
allowfullscreen
title="YouTube Video"
>
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Generations often criticize the generations before them as too rigid, and the generations after them as out-of-control.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In book III of Odes, which is estimated to have been written circa 20 BC, Horace said: “Our sire’s age was worse than our grandsires. We, their sons, are more worthless than they; so in our turn we shall give the world a progeny yet more corrupt.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There is a name for this phenomena, coming forth as a blend of the word Juvenile and Paranoia: Juvenoia. It manifests itself mainly under a distressed concern, or resentful criticism that because of all the new smartphones, the Kardashians, the pop singers, and internet culture the world just isn’t fit to raise well-adjusted kids anymore. It’s also the blown out of proportion animosity some might arbor towards kids these days and how ‘entitled’ they may appear to be, and how they take for ‘granted’ what used to be prized and privileged. Sociologist and director of Crimes against children David Finkelhor came up with the name of the concept in his paper ‘The Internet, Youth Safety and the Problem of “Juvenoia” ’ in 2010, initially stating in his thesis that internet technologies have provoked a widespread wave of anxiety amongst parents because the web is a risk-promoting environment; it is easier for predators to hunt online for their victims and take advantage of them, as it is easier for children to find widely available prohibited sexual materials, and degrade their mental health by exposing themselves to bad influences. Finkelhor proved over all that these worries were actually nonfactual before naming the phenomena: Juvenoia. He also remarked on a funny note that using generational labels, such as calling the precedent generations as close minded and the following as simple-minded, has an amusing tendency to praise those using them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hitchcock wrote in Memoirs of the Bloomsgrove family in 1790: “The free access which many young people have to romances, novels, and plays has poisoned the mind and corrupted the morals of many a promising youth; and prevented others from improving their minds in useful knowledge.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Juvenoia isn’t anything new or only proper to our century: It has been going on for more than a millennia. After all, Colossians 3:20 in the bible “Children, obey your parents in everything, for this pleases the Lord.” is a commandment for a reason; it tried to remediate to the generational clash and reconcile between the wit of the old age and the passion of the youth. Peter the Hermit preached in A.D. 1274: &amp;ldquo;The world is passing through troublous times. The young people of today think of nothing but themselves. They have no reverence for parents or old age. They are impatient of all restraint. They talk as if they knew everything, and what passes for wisdom with us is foolishness with them. As for the girls, they are forward, immodest and unladylike in speech, behavior and dress.&amp;rdquo; It might as well have been a sermon made by a 21st century grandparent. An article published in 1859 in Scientific American kindled against a ‘perverted’ game that weakened morals and physical abilities – chess, and it could also have been used nowadays to criticize video games: “A pernicious excitement to learn and play chess has spread all over the country, and numerous clubs for practicing this game have been formed in cities and villages&amp;hellip;chess is a mere amusement of a very inferior character, which robs the mind of valuable time that might be devoted to nobler acquirements, while it affords no benefit whatever to the body. Chess has acquired a high reputation as being a means to discipline the mind, but persons engaged in sedentary occupations should never practice this cheerless game; they require out-door exercises&amp;ndash;not this sort of mental gladiator ship.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite the ceaseless concerns about the bad influences on the younger generations, and the genuine belief that today’s youth are doing worse than before; kids these days are considered to be the best-behaved generation on record. As originally cited in Vsauce’s video about Juvenoia; The Center of Disease Control published reports and data showing that the Teen birth rate has plummeted from 60 per 1,000 in 1990 to 29 per 1,000 in 2010, and separate data demonstrated that it has also coincided with striking drops in teen abortion rates. The number of teenagers self-harming or killing themselves has dropped dramatically for many years in the US approximately 37.5% from 1990 to 2007. Drinking, smoking, and drug use is down, and instead exercising is up. Math and linguistic aptitudes have increased, juvenile crimes have declined, and bullying and hate speech in schools has dramatically decreased. But, Juvenoia prevails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The point is that Juvenoia remained mostly unchanged; a generation goes and a generation comes but the conflicts between them are doomed to happen. It is an ever-present tendency, and many fields from evolutionary biology, sociology and psychology have speculated on its origins. According to the Darwinian school of thought, as an earthly species; as humans it is totally plausible that we would have been wired with mechanisms to keep our offspring from harm, as we can assume that we would have evolved naturally to prefer the old ways because they are tested and proven to be right rather than the new ways that are untrustworthy and may have unfavorable outcomes. Any manners, or influences that have brought them to the point of a successful reproduction have been satisfactory enough, and any deviation from the same certain choices might be problematic; the survival of the species is critical, due to that many would prefer taking as less risks as possible and using the old ways because they are safer. Children will always appear as vulnerable to their parents because they are more prone to take risks because they have less experience, and therefore less reasons to prefer the old ways. Another annotated reason for Juvenoia is Nostalgia. Parents often talk to their children about their worries by comparing the past to the present, and reflecting a false perception that they were better behaved and in a safer environment. Whereby it only might seem to parents that their children engage in more reckless and risky behaviors than they did when they were younger simply because they had less responsibilities and experience to be aware of the dangers that were always there. This is due to the Selective perception effect, which is the process in which some people might selectively choose to understand and accept only what they want, and ignore anything that opposes their morals. Cognitive psychology tries to explain this as stemming from the fact that our brains perceive the past in a rosy light: The Rosy retrospection effect, as well as Neuroscience found that our memory is consolidated by emotion: we rarely remember boredom in detail, but we recall exciting events in full details, simply because there simply isn’t enough room to remember every single thing or there never was an evolutionary need to recall events in great details. Expressly, you might filter out of your memory the bad times of the past, and still leave raw the present with its petty annoyances because you didn’t fully process it yet, thus you have more chances of preferring the past to the present. Most of the books, songs, movies and slang words and behavior you are fond of are a part of your past, and once past the earliest stages of your life up to your adulthood, in which memories are higher in emotional value, you might feel discomfort towards anything new because you will be more judgmental towards it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be that as it may, it is often omitted that when clarifying the concept of Juvenoia, and its generational quality is the fact that its nature has shifted. Culture used to be crafted by the elites of society for the elites, only the aristocracy could profit from art and literacy. Nowadays culture is dumbed down and distributed to the masses who demand simplicity and rapid gratification instead of complex philosophical truths, or rational thoughts of scholars. The nature of Juvenoia has shifted because of this; it has become widespread after being restricted to a certain intellectual class for centuries. It blossomed into the full blown fear we all know today, and the mocking commentaries have attained unlimited multiple facets; on the health care system, on the educative system, and many other areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if Juvenoia is mainly based on non-factual fears and unbiased ideas; it isn’t harmful. As stated before, it’s a natural phenomenon, therefore positive in healthy doses. The leaning humans have towards worrying has helped draw necessary attention to issues such as pedophilia, mental illness and physical health, and helped correct them. One thing the commenters, and researchers on Juvenoia do at least agree on is that we can educate the general public on dangers without exaggerating their nature; we need to understand the problems of our societies and remediate to them, but for that we only need to be aware of them, and not necessarily to argue or speculate about where they stem from to justify them. Pablo Picasso once said: “We all know that Art is not truth. Art is a lie that makes us realize truth at least the truth that is given us to understand. The artist must know the manner whereby to convince others of the truthfulness of his lies” and the same can be said about Generations and Juvenoia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>REFERENCES:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Definition of Juvenoia:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://fr.wiktionary.org/wiki/juvenoia" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://fr.wiktionary.org/wiki/juvenoia&lt;/a> &lt;br>
&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=juvenoia" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=juvenoia&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Horace’s quote about corrupt progeny:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hitchcock’s quote about corrupted morals:&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Scientific American’s quote about chess:
&lt;a class="link" href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/52209/15-historical-complaints-about-young-people-ruining-everything" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://mentalfloss.com/article/52209/15-historical-complaints-about-young-people-ruining-everything&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The first evocation of the term Juvenoia:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>David Finkelhor:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Finkelhor" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Finkelhor&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.unh.edu/ccrc/researchers/finkelhor-david.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.unh.edu/ccrc/researchers/finkelhor-david.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Internet, Youth Safety and the Problem of “Juvenoia”:
&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.unh.edu/ccrc/pdf/Juvenoia%20paper.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.unh.edu/ccrc/pdf/Juvenoia%20paper.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Colossians 3:20 :
&lt;a class="link" href="http://biblehub.com/commentaries/colossians/3-20.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://biblehub.com/commentaries/colossians/3-20.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Peter the hermit’s quote:
&lt;a class="link" href="http://proto-knowledge.blogspot.com/2010/11/what-is-wrong-with-young-people-today.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://proto-knowledge.blogspot.com/2010/11/what-is-wrong-with-young-people-today.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Vsauce’s video about Juvenoia:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LD0x7ho_IYc" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LD0x7ho_IYc&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Resources used from the video are:
*Vox’s article about generations:&lt;br>
&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.vox.com/2014/5/25/5748178/todays-teenagers-are-the-best-behaved-generation-on-record" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.vox.com/2014/5/25/5748178/todays-teenagers-are-the-best-behaved-generation-on-record&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*Conclusive Pablo Picasso quote about generations and Juvenoia:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/67884-we-all-know-that-art-is-not-truth-art-is" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/67884-we-all-know-that-art-is-not-truth-art-is&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Selective perception effect:
&lt;a class="link" href="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20120416014147/http://counsellingcentral.com/psychology-definition-of-the-week-selective-perception" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://wayback.archive.org/web/20120416014147/http://counsellingcentral.com/psychology-definition-of-the-week-selective-perception&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rosy retrospection:
&lt;a class="link" href="http://wayback.archive.org/web/20151202151926/http://web.mit.edu/curhan/www/docs/Articles/biases/Book_Chapter_Theory_of_Temporal_Adjustments.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://wayback.archive.org/web/20151202151926/http://web.mit.edu/curhan/www/docs/Articles/biases/Book_Chapter_Theory_of_Temporal_Adjustments.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Neuroscience and Cognitive psychology; Memory and emotion:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_and_memory" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotion_and_memory&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>“Culture was dumbed down”:
&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/wired-success/201407/anti-intellectualism-and-the-dumbing-down-america" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/wired-success/201407/anti-intellectualism-and-the-dumbing-down-america&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Supplies of ideas (aqua: Generational conflict):
&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/09/the-generation-of-generations/379989/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2014/09/the-generation-of-generations/379989/&lt;/a>
&lt;a class="link" href="https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/literally-psyched/when-i-was-your-age-or-what-is-it-with-kids-these-days/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/literally-psyched/when-i-was-your-age-or-what-is-it-with-kids-these-days/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>