<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on A Witchy Blog 🧙‍♀</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on A Witchy Blog 🧙‍♀</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://computerwitch.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating through Grief</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/navigating-grief/</guid><description>My father passed away.
And grief became a fever dream where I got to relive all my lost innocence. From shutting the door of the fridge to the smallest possible crease to see when the light would turn off. To the childish game of only stepping in the lithe figure of his shadow… To hearing the clinks of his keys before the door would even open.
I was a tower, a solid structure, built on the crumbling ground.</description></item><item><title>I was a Financial Criminal on Habbo as a Child</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/childhood-memoir/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/childhood-memoir/</guid><description>“Think… Think of something that is important to you…” The bird chirped on the sill of the window. “Of how the colors blend, of the smell of packed mortadella sandwich lunches, yoghurt and gouache. Of kindergarten and sunny days. Of how happy and full your heart was. Of…” And then it flew away, mid-sentence, not letting my imagination catch up to what the chirps and birdsongs could’ve meant. I can’t really think of anything significant.</description></item><item><title>Moral Development in Adolescents</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/moral-development-adolescents/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/moral-development-adolescents/</guid><description>Moral development in adolescence is a recent area of interest in psychological research that achieved maturity. An indicator of that is the numerous published literatures itemizing moral development in adolescence. The interest may push us to want to investigate the reason for which moral development has become a popular topic of interest amongst researchers. The reasons for the attention paid may lie in political and theoretical aims (Hart &amp;amp; Carlo, 2005).</description></item><item><title>A Feast of Gluttony, Desire and Death</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/la-grande-bouffe/</guid><description>Introduction In 1973, Ferreri’s La Grande Bouffe was officially screened at the Cannes Film Festival where it stirred great outrage (Taillibert, 2002). Instantly after its projection, the film placed itself in a tradition of controversial movies that transcend from their initial shock value into debate and deliberation for decades to come. Many questions come to mind when viewing Ferreri’s La Grande Bouffe; is it a jab at the debauchery of the bourgeoisie?</description></item><item><title>Sidi Ali ben Hemdouch: Social and Religious Dynamics in Morocco</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/khalid-mouna/</guid><description>Who is Khalid Mouna? Dr. Khalid Mouna is an anthropologist, professor of sociology at Moulay Ismail University in Meknes. His research publications focus on cannabis, social mobilization and migration. Dr. Mouna’s article, “Le corps à l&amp;rsquo;épreuve du &amp;ldquo;sacré&amp;rdquo;: le rituel du corps à Sidi Ali Ben Hamdouch au Maroc”, delves into the fundamental relationship between social and religious dynamics in Morocco. He studied Sidi Ali ben Hemdouch as a social laboratory to study the construction of sainthood, sacred spaces and the therapeutic power of “L’baraka” or spiritual blessings.</description></item><item><title>The Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/kgb-cold-war/</guid><description>Context and Setting As an aftermath of World War II, an intense economic and military struggle wedged itself between two superpowers: the Soviet Union and the United States. A political and ideological rivalry ensued for decades and marked a period that became known as the Cold War; a term coined by Truman’s political consultant, Bernard Barruch. It was a time was characterized by a series of proxy wars, competitions, atomic and scientific races between the Soviets and the Americans and no direct confrontation.</description></item><item><title>Juvenoia</title><link>https://computerwitch.me/post/juvenoia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://computerwitch.me/post/juvenoia/</guid><description>Generations often criticize the generations before them as too rigid, and the generations after them as out-of-control.
In book III of Odes, which is estimated to have been written circa 20 BC, Horace said: “Our sire’s age was worse than our grandsires. We, their sons, are more worthless than they; so in our turn we shall give the world a progeny yet more corrupt.”
There is a name for this phenomena, coming forth as a blend of the word Juvenile and Paranoia: Juvenoia.</description></item></channel></rss>